So what we're going to do is we're going
to put a break point here on our arrow
for loop and we're going to reload the
page. So we've paused right now. If we
look at numbers, numbers is 456 1 2 3.
We're going to hit the next button and
it's going to set arrow equal to
numbers.length minus one. As long as
it's less than that, it's going to keep
running. Arrow is zero. So we hit next.
So arrow is zero. box is going to be
arrow + 1. So in other words,
um, and as long and it's going to keep
doing that as long as box is less than
the length of numbers, which is six.
We're going to hit next.
All right. So let's hover over those.
Box is in the one position. Arrow is in
the Come on, work with me here. Arrow is
in the zero position. So, we're
comparing.
We're seeing if the number in position
zero is bigger than the number in
position one. So, we're seeing if four
is bigger than five. If it is, we want
to swap. If it's not, we're going to go
to the next. So, it's not. So, we're
going to skip. And now box is going to
increment.
And we're now comparing box, which is in
the two position, to arrow, which is in
the zero position. So now we're
comparing four and six.
Four is not bigger than six. So we'll
skip our for loop and increment our box.
Now box is in the three position and
arrow is still in the zero position. So
we're now comparing zero with 1 2 3 0
with four. So numbers
at the arrow position in the zero
position is four. numbers at the box
position
which is three. Numbers at the box
position is one. Four is bigger than
one. So now we want to swap them. So
we'll hit next. We're going to pull out
a number. Our hold number is four. We
took it out of the numbers array because
number's ray at the zero position was
four. So we pulled it out and we're
storing it. Now, we're going to look at
the number's position at the zero, and
we're going to set it equal to whatever
was in the numbers position at in the
third box. So, we're going to go three
and that's storing a one. So, we're
going to hit next. So, now if we hover
over our numbers array, we now have one
in both spots. Now, we need to put the
four back. So, we're going to say go to
wherever the box position was, wherever
we got the one from, and put in the
number that we were holding. Well, the
number we were holding was four. So,
we'll hit next. And it's now been
entered. So, now if we look at our
numbers, we have successfully bubbled
one all the way up to the top. This loop
will keep running and it will run
exactly like the slideshow that I had in
the last video. So, if you're confused,
I encourage you to go back and watch
that slideshow. Um, but we'll take this
off and we'll put a break point right
before our numbers. And if we continue
now, if we hover over numbers, we can
see it's 1, two, three, four, five, six,
and we are